Guide to the Stanford sports collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford sports collection
1920-2009
1954-1984
SC0630
Stanford University. Department of Athletics.
22.5 Linear feet
Collection primarily includes published items such as programs, media guides, team previews, newsletters, press releases, clippings, and magazine articles, but also includes some game statistics, tickets, photographs, and correspondence. The emphasis is on spring sports such as basketball, track, tennis, baseball, swimming, and golf; there is very little on football. Of note are the photographs of individual golfers illustrating swings from the late 1930s-early 1940s. Collection also includes some materials pertaining to the Golden State Warriors (NBA).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection primarily includes published items such as programs, media guides, team previews, newsletters, press releases, clippings, and magazine articles, but also includes some game statistics, tickets, photographs, and correspondence. The emphasis is on spring sports such as basketball, track, tennis, baseball, swimming, and golf; there is very little on football. Of note are the photographs of individual golfers illustrating swings from the late 1930s-early 1940s. Collection also includes some materials pertaining to the Golden State Warriors (NBA).
Access Terms
McGovern, Lloyd, collector.; Stanford University. Department of Athletics, Physical Education and Recreation. Media Relations.; Basketball--United States.; College sports--California.; Stanford University--Athletics; Stanford University--Athletics--Women; Women's basketball
Collection Contents
- Original Accession, Accession ARCH-2000-095
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2000-177
  - 1971 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field (Stanford Cal in Big Meet) Baseball Swimming and Diving Golf Tennis Crew Senior Recognition Dinner (Gene Washington autograph) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1970 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field (Allen Meredith – Pac 8 Triple Jump Champ) Baseball Swimming Golf Tennis Rugby Senior Recognition Dinner (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1966-67 Stanford Basketball: Press Book Articles Programs – home and away (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1966-67 Basketball (other than Stanford): Basketball Magazine Sports Illustrated – College Basketball Yearbook NBA All Star Game Program + Banquet Warrior Press Book Warrior Programs of games attended Warrior play off + championship UCLA Press Book NCAA Regionals NCAA Championship – Louisville (Missing) UCLA National Champs (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1965-66 Stanford Basketball and Miscellaneous Basketball: Sports Illustrated Converse Yearbook S.F. Warriors programs Peninsula High School Tournament NCAA Regionals Programs (UCLA) NCAA Finals Program (Maryland) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1958 Stanford Spring Sports: Baseball Track Swimming Crew Golf Tennis Spring Football (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1955 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field Baseball Spring Football Crew Tennis Golf Swimming and Diving (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1961 Stanford Spring Sports: Spring Football Track and Field Baseball Tennis Golf Rugby Crew (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1964 Stanford Spring Sports: Track USA-USSR Dual Meet – Los Angeles U.S. Olympic Team Trials – Los Angeles Baseball Rugby Golf Swimming Tennis Crew (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1956 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field Baseball Spring Football Crew Golf Swimming Tennis (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1974 Stanford Spring Sports: Golf = Pac 8 Champions Swimming = Defeated Yale, Michigan, Washington Baseball = Beat USC 5 out of 6 but lost title! Track = No Material Tennis = NCAA Champions! (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1959 Stanford Spring Sports: Baseball Track Swimming Crew Golf Tennis Spring Football and Varsity Alumni Game Rugby (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1962 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field Baseball Rugby Crew Swimming Golf Tennis (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1973 Stanford Spring Sports: Swimming and Diving Rugby Track and Field Baseball Tennis (NCAA Champions) Golf (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1969 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field Baseball Swimming and Diving (Upset USC, Third in Nationals) Golf Tennis Rugby Spring Football Walt Gamage(?) Column (Lloyd) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1971-72 Stanford Basketball: Warriors NCAA Regionals NCAA Championship Converse Yearbook Sports Illustrated Jerry Lucas Autograph (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1972-73 Stanford Basketball: Converse Yearbook Golden State Warriors NCAA regionals NCAA Finals (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1968-69 Stanford Basketball: Highlights (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1967-68 Stanford Basketball: Press Book Articles Hank Luisetti Article Programs, Home and Away (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1967-68 Basketball (Other than Stanford): Sports Illustrated – College Basketball 1st Annual Cable Car Classic UCLA Press Book NCAA Regionals – Albuquerque (missing) NCAA Finals – UCLA (UCLA National Champs) S.F. Warrior Press Book Warrior Programs of Games Attended Warrior Playoff Program (Hawks,Lakers) Converse Yearbook (Missing) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1967 Stanford Spring Sports: Baseball = Third = NCAA World Series Swimming = Won NCAA Championship Track and Field Tennis = Defeated California Golf = 2nd Place = Conference Rugby Crew = Beat California Greatest Overall Year for Indians = article SSUU Gymnastic Championships at Stanford (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1966 Stanford Spring Sports: Track Baseball Swimming Rugby Tennis Golf Crew (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1968-69 Basketball (Other than Stanford): NCAA Regionals = UCLA NCAA Finals = Louisville (UCLA Champions) Sports Illustrated Sporting News Warrior Yearbook Cable Car Classic (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Stanford Spring Sports: Track Baseball (CIBA Champions) Rugby Swimming Golf Tennis Crew (beat Washington) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1972 Stanford Spring Sports: Track Baseball Tennis Swimming Gymnastics Crew Senior Recognition Dinner (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1968 Stanford Spring Sports: Baseball Track and Field Swimming and Diving Rugby Tennis Golf Crew Lacrosse (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1975 Stanford Spring Sports: Men and Women's Department Merged Golf Swimming Baseball (including Diamond Club) Tennis (Fourth in NCAA) Track and Field (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1959 Stanford Sports Articles: Quotes = Chuck Taylor, Recruiting Letters Scouting Reports (Stanford) Stanford Sports Articles All American Football Selections Pre-Season Write-ups = 1955,1956,1957 Jack Cartice (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Panorama of Stanford California Football Game [magazine insert], Nov. 20, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - UCLA football team, strategy against, 1954.. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Pop Warner, 1954 (includes photographs) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Chuck Taylor, career information, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Stanford football, spring 1955 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Stanford spring sports: track, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Stanford football, spring 1957 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Jack Curtice, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Palo Alto Club notices re Stanford sports, ca. 1955-59 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Olympic Track and Field Trials 1960 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - McGovern, Lloyd, correspondence, 1952-57 and undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Stanford spring sports: track, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Stanford spring sports: track, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Stanford basketball 1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 17th Annual NBA All Star Game – press packet, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - McGovern, Lloyd, correspondence, 1963-64 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Stanford spring sports: baseball, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Stanford basketball 1967-68 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Basketball other than Stanford (college and pro) 1967-68, 1967-69 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Stanford basketball 1968-69 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Basketball other than Stanford (pro) 1968-69, 1968-70 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Stanford basketball, 1969/70 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Stanford basketball, 1970/71 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Stanford cross country, water polo, soccer, Fall 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Stanford basketball, 1971/72 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Pro sports events [Peninsula Children’s Center benefit basketball game played by pro football players; NBA all star game; photo of Golden State Warriors], 1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Stanford basketball, 1972/73 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Sport News, Jan. – Feb. 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Sport News, Mar. 1973 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Sport News, Apr. – June 1973 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Annual March of Dimes Decathlon, 1973-75 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Stanford basketball, 1973/74 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Sport News, Jan. – Feb. 1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Sport News, Mar. – Apr. 1974 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Sport News, May – June 1974 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - McGovern, Lloyd, correspondence, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Stanford spring sports: track, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Merger of men’s and women’s athletic departments, 1975 – press release and letter to the Buck Club by Joseph H. Ruetz (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Stanford v. UCLA track meet, 27851 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - NBA basketball, 1976-77 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Stanford basketball, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Stanford spring sports, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Stanford basketball, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Stanford basketball, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Bill Boyd (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: George Bradley (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Art Doering (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Don Haslett (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Gordon Hough (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Don Kennedy (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Don Kennedy (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Sherman Selix (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Guy Showley (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Frank Tatum (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: Dick Wright (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of individual golfers, illustrating swings: unidentified man (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Golf team photos (2 – no dates) (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Football 1973 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Football 1973 – Stanford Daily issues (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Football 1974 Sept., 27273 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Football 1974 Oct., 27303 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Football 1974 Nov., 27334 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Football 1974 miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Football 1974 – Stanford Daily issues (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Football 1977 Sept., 28369 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Football 1977 Oct., 28399 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Football 1977 Nov., 28430 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Football 1977 miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Football 1977 – Stanford Daily issues (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Two certificates re area sports, 1996, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Photograph of Stanford track team, n.d but post 1922 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Issues of the S. F. Chronicle Sporting Green fall 1929 (football) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Issue of the S. F. Examiner Sports (football), Oct. 6, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Issues of the Cal-Bulletin Sports fall 1929 (football) [all of the above are brittle and fragile] (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1973 (First Annual) March of Dimes Decathlon Winners, 1973-75 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1973-74 Basketball: Warriors NCAA NCAA Championships Converse Yearbook SF Basketball (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1963 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field (Second in NCAA) Baseball Rugby (National Collegiate Champs) Swimming Golf Tennis Crew (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1960 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field Baseball Tennis Golf Crew Rugby Boxing Swimming and Diving (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1973-74 Stanford Basketball Season Highlights (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 1960 Final United States Olympic Track and Field Finals (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 1976-77 Basketball: Warriors Converse Yearbook NCAA Regionals NCAA Championship (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - 1978+ Spring Sports (Stanford & non-Stanford) John McEnroe – Tennis (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 1957 Stanford Spring Sports: Track and Field (Payton Jordan's First Year) Crew Baseball Swimming Tennis Golf (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 1969 Basketball (Other than Stanford), 1959 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 1970 Basketball (Other than Stanford) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - 1971 Basketball (Other than Stanford) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 1972 Basketball (Other than Stanford) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - 1973 Basketball (Other than Stanford) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - 1998 Stanford Basketball (clippings) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - 1967-1982 Stanford Track, Tennis, Soccer (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - 1966-1969 Stanford Baseball (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - 1987-1999 Stanford Basketball (Women’s) (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - 1970-1985 Stanford Basketball (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - 1985-1992 Stanford Basketball (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 1992-2000 Stanford Basketball (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - 1969-1984 Stanford Basketball (clippings) (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - 1969-1971 Stanford Basketball Scorecards (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - 1969-1984 Basketball (Stanford & non-Stanford) (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Media Guides, Accession ARCH-2014-037
  - Women's Basketball, 1989-1998 (Box 1)
  - Men's Basketball, 1975-1998 (Box 2)
  - Men's Basketball, 1998-2009 (Box 3)